<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jay&#39;s Musings </title>
    <link>https://devPalacio.github.io/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Jay&#39;s Musings </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>jaypalacio@gmail.com (Jay Palacio)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>jaypalacio@gmail.com (Jay Palacio)</webMaster>
    <copyright>© Jay Palacio</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://devPalacio.github.io/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>JavaScript 30 &amp; code reviews</title>
      <link>https://devPalacio.github.io/blog/blog/code-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>jaypalacio@gmail.com (Jay Palacio)</author>
      <guid>https://devPalacio.github.io/blog/blog/code-review/</guid>
      <description>Javascript30 day 19  Webcam fun?
 Today was the longest and possibly most in depth Javascript30 challenge. The goal was to pulll webcam video, display it on a canvas element, add sliders to adjust the canvas image, and then add a &amp;lsquo;take picture&amp;rsquo; button and display the images at the bottom of the canvas. Pretty legit. Learned a lot about the browser again. Maybe I&amp;rsquo;ll be able to do it without watching a video one day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cloud Genius, VIM, and fish</title>
      <link>https://devPalacio.github.io/blog/blog/cloud-genius/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>jaypalacio@gmail.com (Jay Palacio)</author>
      <guid>https://devPalacio.github.io/blog/blog/cloud-genius/</guid>
      <description>Cloud Genius, VIM, and fish  Customizing EndeavourOS
 Cloud Genius Today kicked off Cloud Genius He puts on a free (for veterans) platform agnostic cloud training platform with an emphasis on open source and using the command line. Day 1 covered some basics such as public/private key pairs, the definition of cloud, the types of cloud ,etc.
He wrote a lot of scripts for ubuntu to automatically provision a custom AWS EC2 instance,and to automatically install needed software for the local development environment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More Dash &#43; Live Coding with AJ Oneil</title>
      <link>https://devPalacio.github.io/blog/blog/falling-behind/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>jaypalacio@gmail.com (Jay Palacio)</author>
      <guid>https://devPalacio.github.io/blog/blog/falling-behind/</guid>
      <description>More Dash + Live Coding with AJ Oneil  Check me out on YouTube
 Getting my ass kicked by a cold right now. Anyways, I missed yesterdays post so this might end up being another long retrospective. The highlight of yesterday was becoming YouTube famous and having a well seasoned JS developer guide me while I added a feature to a codebase he created days earlier. The objective is to extract a trello board, transform it into usable data, and load it into to github.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Event Delegation, Recursion, Local Storage &amp; Dash</title>
      <link>https://devPalacio.github.io/blog/blog/delegation-recursion/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>jaypalacio@gmail.com (Jay Palacio)</author>
      <guid>https://devPalacio.github.io/blog/blog/delegation-recursion/</guid>
      <description>Event Delegation, Recursion, Local Storage &amp;amp; Dash  Learning about the browser and JS
 Today started off pretty good. Continued studying DS&amp;amp;A covering some simple recursion problems. Some pure recursion and some helper function recursion.
Day 15 of Javascript30 was illuminating. I was exposed to localstorage, the proper usage of JSON.parse() &amp;amp; JSON.stringify() and event delegation. Apparently it&amp;rsquo;s just a fancy term for having an event listener on a parent node listening for and acting on events from its children.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hugo, templates, date formats, bug hunting</title>
      <link>https://devPalacio.github.io/blog/blog/hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>jaypalacio@gmail.com (Jay Palacio)</author>
      <guid>https://devPalacio.github.io/blog/blog/hugo/</guid>
      <description>I reached the stage of frustration in which you change 10 things at once and then you&amp;rsquo;re not really sure what fixed it. At least that&amp;rsquo;s how I felt.
When I was adding content to this blog via Bliss I noted my post date was being set as Jan 1, 0001.
This led me into the rabbit hole of how Hugo (the really fast static site builder that Bliss uses) uses templates, dates, config files, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ETL with JS and a job interview</title>
      <link>https://devPalacio.github.io/blog/blog/post/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>jaypalacio@gmail.com (Jay Palacio)</author>
      <guid>https://devPalacio.github.io/blog/blog/post/</guid>
      <description>Did a little bit of JavaScript today working on an open source project called Trello Github ETL  The goal is to ETL: extract data in the form of a JSON file from Trello, transform it into something github projects beta understands, and load it into github. Got some experience getting oriented in a new codebase, setting ENV variables and creating GH tokens and working in VIM. Extracted labels for the trello cards from the JSON  I got more comfortable working in a plain node.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello world, first post</title>
      <link>https://devPalacio.github.io/blog/blog/hello-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>jaypalacio@gmail.com (Jay Palacio)</author>
      <guid>https://devPalacio.github.io/blog/blog/hello-world/</guid>
      <description>An overview of the resources I&amp;rsquo;ve found helpful while learning to code. I seriously started learning on September 29th 2019. So there&amp;rsquo;s a lot of catching up to do here
The first resource I started seriously attempting to learn is the famous CS50x I took away a lot from it, and actually enjoyed it. I stopped on Week 5, its one of my goals to finish it this year. Learning JavaScript took precedence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://devPalacio.github.io/blog/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>jaypalacio@gmail.com (Jay Palacio)</author>
      <guid>https://devPalacio.github.io/blog/about/</guid>
      <description>Did 12 years in the Coast Guard fixing, flying on, and hoisting from Helicopters.
Spent my lifetime breaking/fixing/breaking/fixing computers, finally trying to earn a living doing it.
I like riding bikes, BJJ, and local/sustainable food.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://devPalacio.github.io/blog/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>jaypalacio@gmail.com (Jay Palacio)</author>
      <guid>https://devPalacio.github.io/blog/contact/</guid>
      <description>Give me a holler if you want to chat.
jaypalacio@gmail.com \
Clearwater, Florida</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
